# DOAA SAAFAN

# **UX/UI** Designer

Dublin, Ohio 43017 | Phone: +1-614-929-8196 | Email: doaasaafan16@gmail.com

Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/doaa-saafan-32923b64/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/doaa-saafan-32923b64/</a>
Portfolio: <a href="https://doaasaafan.github.io/UX\_UI\_HW\_19/">https://doaasaafan.github.io/UX\_UI\_HW\_19/</a>

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

A dedicated UX/UI Designer who has recently completed the UX/UI bootcamp program at Ohio State University in 2024. My passion lies in creating interfaces that are not only usable, enjoyable, and accessible but also tailored to meet the diverse needs of users.

Prior to embarking on my journey in UX/UI design, I accumulated over ten years of experience in various roles such as system administration, customer service, and office administration. This extensive background has equipped me with a strong foundation in understanding user needs and providing exceptional service.

Completing the UX/UI Bootcamp at OSU was a significant milestone in my journey, equipping me with the skills and confidence to pursue a fulfilling career in UX/UI design.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Google Suite . Microsoft Office . Trello . Slack . Zoom . User Research . Information Architecture . Storyboarding . User Journey Mapping . Surveys . Wireframing . Responsive Design . Usability Testing . Iterative Design Thinking . User Interface Prototyping . Heuristic Evaluation Testing . Adobe XD . Sketch . Figma . Miro . HTML . CSS . Java . Java Script . PHP . SQL . DB2 . Python

#### **PROJECTS**

### **Peer to Peer Mobile Application**

- Design a mobile application for self storage which helps anyone to rent out spaces he needs from someone near him or list unused space for rent and increase his income
- Used Figma and Google suite

### **US Department of Interior Desktop Application**

- Redesign the website of the US Department of Interior
- Used Figma and Google suite.

# Hope for children Desktop Application

[https://doaasaafan.github.io/UX UI HW 20/]

- Redesign the website of Hope for Children, a non profit charity website which collects donations to aid sexually and physically abused children
- Used Figma and Google suite

### My personal Portfolio

[https://doaasaafan.github.io/UX UI HW 19/]

• Create my portfolio webpage using Visual Studio code 2, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and GitHub.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**UX/UI Designer** 

Self-employed

Ohio/United States

Sep 2024 - present

- Conducting user research to understand customer needs, pain points, and preferences
- Creating wireframes, prototypes, and mockups to visualize and test design concepts
- Collaborating with cross functional teams to ensure design alignment with business goals
- Performing usability testing to gather feedback and iterate on design solutions
- Skilled in using Figma, Sketch, Miro and Adobe XD

Stay-at-home Mom

Self-employed

Charles I have a Maria

Ohio/United States 2015 - 2024

- Managed household and family responsibilities, including childcare and housekeeping
- Organized and planned family events and activities
- Network with friends creating a Whatsapp group to support learning and set up activities for kids
- Volunteered in handling and organizings parties in the mosque
- Volunteered as an Arabic Language teacher in a program for young children at the mosque
- Volunteered as a Room Parent in Glacier Ridge Elementary School

## Office Manager and Administration Supervisor

Raya Information Technology

Cairo/Egypt 2009 - 2015

- Organize and manage weekly and monthly schedules and appointments for the Services Director.
- Facilitate and support departments in their HR and Finance requests
- Plan and organize weekly review meetings as well as minutes of meeting and efficient actions follow up
- Responsible for all travel reservations
- Follow up all Customer Complaints
- Full System Administration, Customizing and Reporting [CRM and HP Open view ]

## **EDUCATION**

The Ohio State University College of Engineering

OSU UX/UI bootcamp

Ohio/United States October 2024

**IBM**Application Development Boot Camp

Cairo, Egypt

Ain Shams University

Cairo, Egypt

Bachelor of Arts English language and Literature

2005

2016